# DAVEN CHANG

University of Maryland College Park B.S. in CS/ML GPA: 3.95

### SUMMARY

Passionate about software development and machine learning with a growing interest in Generative Al. Expansive Python skills and experience developed through countless personal projects. Comfortable with other programming languages. Collaborative team player with a strong work ethic and a passion for learning and growth.

dchang1iz@gmail.com davenc.dev

daven-c

+1 703-966-4174 Pairfax, Virginia

daven-chang

# SKILLS

Python, Java, C, C++, Mojo, HTML, CSS, Languages:

Javascript, Arduino.

Technologies: VSCode, Git, Linux, Numpy, Pandas, Ten-

sorflow, Keras, OpenCV, PyTorch, Matplotlib, Mediapipe, Flask, Typing, RegEx.

# **EDUCATION**

8/2023 - Present CS/ML @ University of Maryland College Park School

Researcher in the the FIRE research program in Sustainability Analytics. Member of the BigThink AI club, and the Taiwanese American Student Association (TASA).

Inspirit AI - AI Scholar 7/2023 - 8/2023

Program

Built cifar-10 classifiers with KNNs and CNNs. Combined NLP and DNN through LSTMs, RNN, and transformers, to predict stock prices from news and market history.

**BWSI - COGWORKS** 6/2023 - 6/2023

Program

Completed pre-requisite course on Autonomous Cognitive Assistants. Learned version control with Git, and advanced knowledge of Python and NLP techniques.

### **PROJECTS**

Hackathon **Helping Hands**  https://devpost.com/software/helpinghands-myl8ox

Developed a program that utilizes computer vision and the onboard webcam to allow users to move, click, and scroll the mouse remotely using their hands. Used Python, mediapipe, cv2, numpy, pyautogui.

Website

https://davenc.dev

Started work on a personal website as a way of learning HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Learned networking principles such as DNS, IP addresses, and http/tcp as well. Planning to incorporate Node, is and other frameworks

Personal

**DiaitGAN** 

https://github.com/daven-c/DigitGAN

Created, trained, and fine-tuned GANs in pytorch capable of generating images of numbers similar to the MNIST dataset. Tested both Deep Neural Networks and Convolutional Neural Networks to improve performance.

Personal

**Digit Classifier** 

https://davenc.dev

Created and trained a Convolutional Neural Network with keras to identify a digit drawn on a grid-based UI created using pygame. Included a system of easily saving and loading the best models.

Personal

A Star Visualizer

https://github.com/daven-c/A-Star-Visualizer

Created a grid-based visualizer which includes the ability to place obstacles on a board consisting of a start and end tile. Once run, the program searches for the best path around the obstacles from the start tile to end tile using the A Star pathing algorithm.

# **EXPERIENCE**

2/2023 - Present Freelance

- · Developed first paid website, jewel-inthelotus.com.
- Developed automated discord bots that managed servers, initiated events, created games, and boosted member interaction.
- · Built mock games including 2048 and Snake using the pygame library.

8/2021 - 6/2023

Fairfax Regional Library

- Tutored students ranging from K-10 in core subjects including math, science, history, and english.
- Tutored every Wednesday and Sunday.

## COURSEWORK

· Intro to Object Oriented Programming I/II, Data Structures and Algorithms, Intro to Computer Systems, Discrete Structures, Organization of Programming Languages, Algorithms, Calculus I/II, Linear Algebra.